# PRATIKSHA MISHRA

Email- pratikshamishra2018@gmail.com

Contact- +91 9981050947



### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Pratiksha has 3+ year of IT experience, currently working in Deloitte as Analyst. Has strong experience in automation testing Selenium and JAVA development, API Testing and worked with TOSCA automation. Has good knowledge of various phases of Software Development and Testing Life Cycle, as well as of Agile way of working. Has been trained in CICD and DOJO.

#### **CARRER GOAL**

Looking for an opportunity to leverage my experience, expertise, analytical & Solutioning thinking.

# **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Responsible for End-to-End Implementation.
- Involving in design, development, coding, testing, and debugging of system software.
- Preparing technical specifications according to business needs.
- Automation scripting of regression cases using Selenium WebDriver.
- Involved in all Agile ceremonies.
- Involve in Smoke testing
- Involved in Regression testing
- Knowledge transfer/ Training for new hires in team
- Bug report and retest
- Involve in Demo for Client for FAT approval
- Interacting with clients and onsite team on regular basis to gather user requirements.
- Support other team with testing to meet there in sprint goal.

# Technical Experience:

- Testing Tools: Selenium, Postman, TOSCA
- Defect Tracking Tools: JIRA
- Programming Language: Core Java, OOPs Concepts
- IDE: Eclipse
- Build, versioning, and CI Tools: MAVEN, GIT, Jenkins
- Other Test Frameworks: Junit & TestNG
- Database: MySQL, SYBASE
- Batch: JAMES
- Automation: FitNesse, Macros, TOSCA
- Smoke testing, Regression Testing
- Test life cycle ALM

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

#### Analyst – Deloitte USI

August 2021 – Present

(Project Description): Working on Health domain, Angular based application UI and Services

- Analyzing story as per business requirement with Application Consultants
- Collaboration with development team to come up with test scenarios
- Creation of Test plan, and respective scenarios and assign it into ALM for monitoring
- Execution of **Smoke test** after each deployment
- Execution of API testing with help Postman tool
- Working in Azure blob storage and Data Lake for testing of the documents
- Automation of API for regression suite with help of TOSCA
- Automation of UI with the Selenium Framework using TestNG
- Basis of Implementation of CDCD with help of **Jenkins**

#### **Analyst – Deloitte USI**

February 2021-August 2021

(Project Description): Working on Health domain, desktop-based Application for Pharmacy

- Analyzing story as per business requirement with Application Consultants
- Collaboration with development team to come up with test scenarios
- Creation of Test plan, and respective scenarios and assign it into ALM for monitoring
- Execution of Smoke test after each deployment
- Execution of regression and manual test and come up with test result
- Manual tests include end to end testing multi version testing and scenario-based testing
- Automation of regression suite with help of **TOSCA** tool

#### **Test Engineer – Infosys**

March 2019-Januay 2021

(Project Description): Working on Bank domain, Desktop based Application for Mortgage system

- Analyzing story as per business requirement with Application Consultants
- Collaborate with development team to create Test plan
- Creation of Test case for Manual Testing as per Requirement
- Close monitoring with Business through timely and precise execution of manual /automated test
- Execution involves batch running with JAMS job, SQL run, Application monitoring and performing Flows
- Document software product defect and track them with Jira
- Automation in desktop application with Macros and Fitness

#### **Test Engineer – Infosys**

October 2018- February 2019

(**Project Description**): Automation framework for web-based applications which helps user to create POM, Test cases automatically. These test cases can be executed as test plan and reports which are in sync with JIRA can be generated

- Developing Codes based on User Requirements: Smart forms designing & execution.
- Report implementations.
- Involved in requirement analysis with product owner and application development in the **Agile- DevOps methodology.**
- Creation of MySQL database & fetching data and validate that data against actual data.
- Validation of data perform by using **Assertion**.
- Creating Test Case and generation of Test plans and execution.
- Has been involved in Unit, functional & regression testing of the tool.

### **Certifications:**

- Microsoft Certified in Azure Data Fundamentals
- Global Agile certified *Infosys internal*
- Basic and Advance Selenium certified *Infosys internal*
- Tricentis Certified TOSCA Automation Specialist Level 1
- Tricentis Certified TOSCA Automation Specialist Level 2
- Tricentis Certified TOSCA Automation Specialist For API

### Awards and Recognition:

- **Spot Award** for Outstanding performer in Team by **Deloitte** April 2021
- **Spot Award** for Consistent and dedicated performer and proven as assert for team by **Deloitte** October 2021
- **Insta Award** for Excellent performer and on completion of SDET certificate by **Infosys** September 2021

# **Qualifications:**

- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer science from BIT Raipur with first division.
- 12th from BSP S.S.S sector 10 Bhilai (CBSE) with 84.5%.
- 10th from BSP S.S.S sector 10 Bhilai (CBSE) with 9.2 CGPA.